Out of control. As the man tried to swim in the speedboat round, the steering wheel came away in his hands.
He waved desperately to his companion, who had been water-skiing for the last fifty minutes.
Both men had hardly had time to realize what was happening when they were swooped violently into the sea.
The speedboat had struck a boil, but it continued to move very quickly across the water.
Both men had just begun to swim towards the shore.
When they noised with dismay,
the speedboat was moving in a cycle.
It now came straight towards them at tremendous speed in less than a minute.
It rolled past them only a few feet away.
After it had passed, they swam on as quickly as they could,
because they knew that
the boat would soon return.
They had just had enough time to swim out of danger
when the boat again completely acycled on this course.
However, it had slowed down considerably.
The petrol had nearly all been used up.
Before long,
the noise dropped completely,
and the boat began to draft gently across the water.